<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<BuildingInformation>
  <Classification>
    <System>
      <Name>NATSPEC Worksections</Name>
      <EditionVersion>2017</EditionVersion>
      <EditionDate>
        <Year>2017</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </EditionDate>
      <Description>NATSPEC is the National Master Specification for use with projects of all types and sizes. For each project, you select  the appropriate NATSPEC worksections from the National Classification System</Description>
      <Source>http://www.natspec.com.au</Source>
      <Items>
        <Item>
          <ID>00</ID>
          <Name>PLANNING AND DESIGN (AUS-SPEC)</Name>
          <Description/>
          <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
          <Children>
            <Item>
              <ID>001</ID>
              <Name>General</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0010</ID>
                  <Name>Quality requirements for design</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to providing a quality management system to AS/NZS ISO 9001 for engineering design processes required by Council for engineering works. The requirements are applicable to all design work whether undertaken by designers within Council, a Consultant or a Subconsultant.It describes conditions and criteria that are not applicable to Council requirements.Edit this worksection Template to suit Council specific project requirements.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0011</ID>
                  <Name>Development and subdivision of land</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0012</ID>
                  <Name>Waterfront development</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to design and documentation requirements for waterway facilities and structures for canal type subdivisions or developments with water frontages to natural waterways.It may describes conditions and criteria that are not applicable to Council requirements. If required, amend the content to align with these requirements.Edit this worksection Template to create Council Engineering guidelines for the development or a project specific design brief as required.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0013</ID>
                  <Name>Bushfire protection</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the design and documentation requirements for bushfire protection facilities for urban and rural subdivisions.It may describe conditions and criteria that are not applicable to the Council’s requirements. If required, amend the content to align with these requirements.Edit this worksection Template to create Council Engineering guidelines or a project specific design brief as required.Refer also to NATSPEC TECHnote DES 018 for a summary on factors influencing bushfires and the planning, construction and maintenance requirements for bushfire protection.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>002</ID>
              <Name>Open spaces</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0021</ID>
                  <Name>Site regrading</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the design and documentation requirements for site regrading for both Council works and land development and subdivisions.It may describe conditions and criteria that are not applicable to Council’s requirements. If required, amend the content to align with these requirements.Edit this worksection Template to create Council Engineering guidelines or a project specific design brief as required.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>004</ID>
              <Name>Road reserve</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0041</ID>
                  <Name>Geometric road layout</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the geometric layout design of minor roadworks, for safety, improved amenity and to reduce pedestrian/vehicular conflicts. It applies to minor roads within the domain of urban and regional Councils. For major roads and highways, refer to the relevant State Road Authority. Specific State and Territory requirements must be included in addition to Austroads requirements.It may describe conditions and criteria that are not applicable to Council requirements. If required, amend the content to align with these requirements.Edit this worksection Template to create Council Engineering guidelines for development or a project specific design brief as required.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0042</ID>
                  <Name>Pavement design</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the design and documentation for new road pavements and rehabilitation of existing pavements. It includes procedures for designing the following type of pavements:Flexible pavements of unbound granular materials.Flexible pavements of one or more bound layers, including pavements containing asphalt layers other than thin asphalt wearing surfaces.Rigid pavements (i.e. cement concrete pavements).Segmental concrete or clay paving with base and subbase.Unsealed pavements.It may describe conditions and criteria that are not applicable to Council’s requirements. If required, amend the content to align with these requirements.Edit this worksection Template to create Council Engineering guidelines or a project specific design brief as required.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0043</ID>
                  <Name>Subsurface drainage (Design)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the design and documentation of subsurface drainage systems for new and existing road pavement and/or subgrade including:Subsoil and formation drains.Pavement drains.Drainage blankets.It may describe conditions and criteria which are not applicable to the Council’s requirements. If required, amend the content to align with these requirements.Edit this worksection Template to create Council Engineering development guidelines or a project specific design brief as required.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0044</ID>
                  <Name>Pathways and cycleways (Design)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the design and documentation requirements for various types of cycleways and pathways. It is not applicable to paths and cycleways in complex intersections, roundabouts or railway crossings.It may describe conditions and criteria that are not be applicable to the Council’s requirements. If required, amend the content to align with these requirements.Edit this worksection Template to create Council Engineering guidelines for development or a project specific design brief as required.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>006</ID>
              <Name>Bridges</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0061</ID>
                  <Name>Bridges and related structures</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to design and documentation requirements for the following structures:Road traffic bridges.Pedestrian bridges including bicycle and wheelchair access.Structures other than bridges associated with bridge construction e.g. culverts, retaining structures, sign supporting structures and noise barriers.Structures providing public safety, e.g. safety barriers, safety rails, protection screens and street lighting poles.Temporary works.It may describe conditions and criteria that are not applicable to Council requirements. If required, amend the content to align with these requirements.Edit this worksection Template to create Council Engineering guidelines for development or a project specific design brief as required.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>007</ID>
              <Name>Public utilities</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0071</ID>
                  <Name>Water supply - reticulation (Design)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to design and documentation requirements for drinking and non-drinking water reticulation systems, excluding pump stations, generally up to and including DN 375 either, as a stand-alone project or as part of a development in a Council area, where Council is responsible for the provision and maintenance of water supply systems. It is applicable to new water supply systems or upgrades to existing water supply systems. It is aligned with, and relies on, the requirements of WSA 03 and provides the mechanism to document specific Water Agency requirements.It may describe conditions and criteria that are not applicable to Council requirements. If required, amend the content to align with these requirements.Edit this worksection Template to create Council Engineering guidelines for development or a project specific design brief as required.Water Agency requirements take precedence over any conflicting technical requirements. Amend this Template to reflect local and state regulations. All designs must be approved by the Water Agency. This Template allows for the Water Agency to be the Council or any other Water Authority. It does not include administrative items for approval with the Water Agency.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0072</ID>
                  <Name>Water supply - pump stations (Design)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to design and documentation requirements for in-line pressure booster pump stations for use with drinking and non-drinking water reticulation systems generally up to and including DN 375. It is not intended for the design of Transfer, Distribution or Source water supply pump stations. It is applicable to new water supply systems or upgrades to existing water supply systems. It is aligned with, and relies on, the requirements of WSA 03 and provides the mechanism to document specific Water Agency requirements.It may describe conditions and criteria that are not applicable to Council requirements. If required, amend the content to align with these requirements.Edit this worksection Template to create Council Engineering guidelines for development or a project specific design brief as required.Water Agency requirements take precedence over any conflicting technical requirements. Amend this Template to reflect local and state regulations. All designs must be approved by the Water Agency. This Template allows for the Water Agency to be the Council or any other Water Authority. It does not include administrative items for approval with the Water Agency.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0074</ID>
                  <Name>Stormwater drainage (Design)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the design and documentation requirements for stormwater drainage systems for urban and regional areas. It covers hydrology and hydraulic design for a total stormwater drainage system and includes Water Sensitive Urban Design principles of stormwater harvesting and re-use.It assumes that if the Council does not provide a Handbook for drainage design criteria to the design engineer, the alternative cited documents for design criteria are used.It may describe conditions and criteria that are not applicable to Council requirements. If required, amend the content to align with these requirements.Edit this worksection Template to create Council engineering guidelines or a project specific design brief as required.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0075</ID>
                  <Name>Control of erosion and sedimentation (Design)</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0076</ID>
                  <Name>Sewerage systems - reticulation (Design)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to design and documentation requirements for a sewerage system, either a stand-alone project or part of a development in a regional Council area.The worksection provides for the design of the following elements of the sewerage system:Gravity, pressure and vacuum sewers up to DN 600 nominal size.Rising mains up to DN 600 nominal size.Standard appurtenances such as maintenance holes, maintenance shafts and property connection sewers.This worksection is aligned to the Water Services Association of Australia WSA 02, WSA 04, WSA 06and WSA 07.Water Agency requirements take precedence to any conflicting technical requirements. This is a Template and needs to be amended to reflect the local and state regulations. All designs must be approved by the Water Agency. This Template allows for the Water Agency to be the Council or another Authority. This worksection does not include administrative items for approval with the Water Agency.It may describe conditions and criteria that are not applicable to Council requirements. If required, amend the content to align with these requirements.Edit this worksection Template to create Council Engineering guidelines for development or a project specific design brief as required.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0077</ID>
                  <Name>Sewerage systems -  pump stations (Design)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the design and documentation requirements of pump stations, usually limited to single wells with submersible pumps up to and including 200L/s and DN 375 (DN 450 for PE). The worksection provides for the design of the pumps for a sewerage system which is either a stand-alone project or part of a regional Council development.This worksection is aligned to the Water Services Association of Australia WSA 04 the Sewage pumping station code of Australia, WSA 06 Vacuum sewerage code of Australia and WSA 07 Pressure sewerage code of Australia.It may describe conditions and criteria that are not applicable to Council requirements. If required, amend the content to align with these requirements.Edit this worksection Template to create Council Engineering guidelines for development or a project specific design brief as required.Water Agency requirements take precedence to any conflicting technical requirements. This is a Template and needs to be amended to reflect the local and state regulations. All designs must be approved by the Water Agency. The Water Agency may be the Council or other Authority. This worksection does not include administrative items for approval with the Water Agency.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
          </Children>
        </Item>
        <Item>
          <ID>01</ID>
          <Name>GENERAL</Name>
          <Description/>
          <Availability>None</Availability>
          <Children>
            <Item>
              <ID>011</ID>
              <Name>Documentation</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>None</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0110</ID>
                  <Name>Specification cover sheet</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0111</ID>
                  <Name>Tendering cover sheet</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0112</ID>
                  <Name>Multiple contracts cover sheet</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to general structural steel framing in buildings, and associated structures. It includes cold-formed purlins and girts used in conjunction with structural steelwork. It covers welding, bolting, surface preparation and treatment of structural steelwork, and architecturally exposed structural steelwork (AESS).</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0113</ID>
                  <Name>Amendment record sheet</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>012</ID>
              <Name>Tendering</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>None</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0120</ID>
                  <Name>Pre-tendering contract preparation (AUS-SPEC)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is a framework for the development of request for tender documents based on AUS-SPEC worksections. It includes a cover page and sets out the documents required for Part A Tender information and Part B Contract documentation volumes.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0121</ID>
                  <Name>Tendering</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template reflects the principles of the main Australian codes of practice, including AS 4120 which is cited in a number of state government's codes of practice. The worksection assumes head-contract tendering. It is applicable to non-contractual material and so does not form part of the contract documents. A tender pro-forma is attached to cover tender offers in the form of a lump sum.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0122</ID>
                  <Name>Information for tenderers (AUS-SPEC)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to an introductory document to enable prospective Tenderers to determine whether the scope and type of works in the proposed Contract is within their capability. It is a separate document to, but aligned with, 0123 Conditions of tendering.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0123</ID>
                  <Name>Conditions of tendering (AUS-SPEC)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to conditions of tendering including contract information, tender submission requirements, tender evaluation and selection criteria. It assumes traditional paper-based tendering methods but this worksection can be adapted to suit digital distribution and eTendering (electronic tendering system). If using eTendering, consult with the administrators of the system about the standard forms provided as part of the system and about amending these to suit your requirements. The worksection should align with 0122 Information for tenderers, a separate, introductory document for prospective Tenderers. This worksection does not form part of the contract documents.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0124</ID>
                  <Name>Tender submission documents (AUS-SPEC)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the returnable forms and schedules nominated by the Principal for completion by the Contractor for inclusion in the Tender submission. The completed worksection forms VOLUME 4 - Tender submission documents of the request for tender (RFT). It assumes traditional paper-based tendering methods but this worksection can be adapted to suit digital distribution and eTendering (electronic tendering system). If using eTendering, consult with the administrators of the system about the standard forms provided as part of the system and about amending these to suit your requirements.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0125</ID>
                  <Name>Standard contract checklists (AUS-SPEC)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection applies to standard contracts and provides checklists for contract compilation, tender preparation, receipt of tenders and tender assessment.These checklists should be used in conjunction with TG 102 Guidelines for Principals – standard contracts.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0126</ID>
                  <Name>Period supply and service checklist (AUS-SPEC)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection applies to period supply and service contracts and provides a checklist for commissioning of documentation, determination of technical requirements, document finalisation approval and the tender advertisement template.These checklists should be used in conjunction with TG 103 Guidelines for Principals – period supply and service contracts.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0127</ID>
                  <Name>Commissioning - information</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template provides non-contractual information for the contractor when the owner requires a Commissioning Authority (CxA) to oversee the commissioning process for the whole, or a defined part of a project. It is based on the commissioning process described in ASHRAE Guideline 0.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>013</ID>
              <Name>Generic preliminaries</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>None</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0131</ID>
                  <Name>Preliminaries (Generic)</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0133</ID>
                  <Name>Preliminaries (Interior and alterations)</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0134</ID>
                  <Name>General requirements (Supply) (AUS-SPEC)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the general requirements for a supply contract and includes the supply of labour, materials and plant to carry out the works. This worksection can be used for minor construction works. For major construction works, use 0136 General requirements (Construction).</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0135</ID>
                  <Name>General requirements (Services) (AUS-SPEC)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the general requirements for a supply and service contract. The work under this contract comprises of supply of labour, materials and equipment necessary to carry out the services specified. It can be used for a single contract for provision of general goods and services over a period of time.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0136</ID>
                  <Name>General requirements (Construction) (AUS-SPEC)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the site requirements of the principal for minor civil works construction projects, including site acess, restrictions and investigations, superintendent’s site office, project signage, survey control, principal supplied items, and existing utilities services. It also draws together administrative material common to the worksections, including referenced documents, interpretation, inspection and tests, contractor’s submissions, materials and products and work-as-executed drawings.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0138</ID>
                  <Name>Multiple contracts</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to projects to be let as several prime contract packages, also known as trade package contracts and separate contracts. It deals with the interfaces between the contracts and provides a framework for scheduling the boundaries of responsibility between the contractor and the principal or other contractors, on behalf of the principal.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>014</ID>
              <Name>Contract preliminaries</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>None</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0140</ID>
                  <Name>Preliminaries - ABIC BW-1</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0141</ID>
                  <Name>Preliminaries - ABIC MW-2008</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0142</ID>
                  <Name>Preliminaries - ABIC MW-2011 C QLD</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0143</ID>
                  <Name>Preliminaries - AS 2124</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0144</ID>
                  <Name>Preliminaries - AS 4000</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0145</ID>
                  <Name>Preliminaries - AS 4905</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0146</ID>
                  <Name>Preliminaries - AS 4902</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0147</ID>
                  <Name>Conditions of contract (AUS-SPEC)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the General conditions of contract, Annexures to the contract and Special conditions of contract. The completed worksection forms VOLUME 1 – Conditions of contract. This worksection is based on AS 2124 General conditions of contract. Amend this document for use with other general conditions of contract, special conditions, WHS and environmental requirements. See NATSPEC disclaimer on the use of this worksection for this and other contracts.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0148</ID>
                  <Name>Preliminaries - ABIC EW-1</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>015</ID>
              <Name>Schedule of rates (AUS-SPEC)</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>None</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0152</ID>
                  <Name>Schedule of rates - supply projects</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0153</ID>
                  <Name>Schedules-period supply and service</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the schedule of rates requirements for tenderers for period supply and service (Supply and Deliver) contracts.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>016</ID>
              <Name>Quality assurance</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>None</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0160</ID>
                  <Name>Quality</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template applies to the selection and implementation of a project Quality Management System based on AS/NZS ISO 9001. It includes the submission of a Quality Plan from a contractor having an approved Quality Manual.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0161</ID>
                  <Name>Quality (Construction) (AUS-SPEC)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the contractual requirements for the quality management system (QMS) documentation and operation for construction activities. It contains umbrella requirements for quality control and testing and includes the following:Developing and implementing a project QMS to AS/NZS ISO 9001.Developing and implementing a project quality plan to cover all work under the contract including permanent works, temporary works, on-site and off-site works.Keeping quality records.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0162</ID>
                  <Name>Quality (Supply) (AUS-SPEC)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the quality requirements for delivery documentation of a quality assured product where the Producer has third party certification of an implemented quality system conforming to AS/NZS ISO 9001.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0164</ID>
                  <Name>Commissioning</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to projects in which the owner requires a Commissioning Authority (CxA) to oversee a commissioning process for the whole of the project. It details minimum requirements for the commissioning process during the construction phase without focusing upon specific building types, systems or assemblies, or on specific project sizes. It is based on the commissioning process described in ASHRAE Guideline 0. Commissioning requirements for individual components and systems are documented in their respective worksections, for example, commissioning of HVAC systems is dealt with in 0791 Mechanical commissioning.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0163</ID>
                  <Name>Quality (Delivery) (AUS-SPEC)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the quality requirements for delivery of products for acceptance by the Principal in conforming to AS/NZS ISO 9001.Product delivery includes the following activities:Handling.Storage.Packaging.Preservation.Delivery.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0167</ID>
                  <Name>Integrated management (AUS-SPEC)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the documentation and operation of a system that collects the operating procedures of Quality requirements, Environmental requirements and Work Health and Safety into a single integrated management system.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0168</ID>
                  <Name>Green star - as built submissions</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0169</ID>
                  <Name>Green star - office as built submissions</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>017</ID>
              <Name>General requirements</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>None</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0171</ID>
                  <Name>General requirements</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template draws together administrative material which is common to the technical worksections for new work, interiors and for alterations and additions, including services. It should therefore be brought to the attention of subcontractors and others using that material. Each technical worksection includes a cross reference to that effect. 0171 General requirements cover topics such as referenced documents, interpretation, inspection and tests, samples and contractor’s submissions, materials and components, bushfire resistance, installation, marking and completion.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>018</ID>
              <Name>Common requirements</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>None</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0181</ID>
                  <Name>Adhesives, sealants and fasteners</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the commonly used adhesives, sealants and fasteners and provides basic defaults for projects requiring adhesives, sealants and fasteners, as part of general construction.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0182</ID>
                  <Name>Fire-stopping</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the fire-stopping requirements of BCA deemed-to-satisfy clauses BCA C3.15 and BCA C3.16.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0183</ID>
                  <Name>Metals and prefinishes</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to common metals and metal alloys, and prefinishes.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0184</ID>
                  <Name>Termite management</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to various physical and chemical and systems which may be used, alone or in combination, for termite management. The various systems are located together in the one worksection as their effectiveness relies on the integration of the chosen systems.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0185</ID>
                  <Name>Timber products, finishes and treatment</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the certification, durability and quality conformance of timber products. It includes preservative treatments to the AS 1604 series, moisture content and fire-resistance. State legislation will override some of the provisions of this worksection.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0186</ID>
                  <Name>Building IT components</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>019</ID>
              <Name>Sundry installations</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>None</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0191</ID>
                  <Name>Sundry items</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to building components that may not obviously belong to a particular worksection or alternatively, could reasonably belong to a number of worksections. They are generally small scale proprietary components made from a range of materials, and can be installed in a range of interior or exterior locations. Custom-made items are better located in the appropriate worksection, e.g. 0552 Metalwork – fabricated for predominantly metal items, or items to be made by a metal fabricator.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0192</ID>
                  <Name>Structural steel components</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0193</ID>
                  <Name>Roof access safety systems</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the design, supply, installation and maintenance of building access safety systems comprising industrial fall arrest and rope access systems. It includes anchors and accessories for rope access and ladders for roof safety systems.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0194</ID>
                  <Name>Door seals and window seals</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0195</ID>
                  <Name>Tactile indicators and stair nosings</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
          </Children>
        </Item>
        <Item>
          <ID>02</ID>
          <Name>SITE, URBAN AND OPEN SPACES</Name>
          <Description/>
          <Availability>None</Availability>
          <Children>
            <Item>
              <ID>020</ID>
              <Name>Demolition</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>None</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0201</ID>
                  <Name>Demolition</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to demolition of existing buildings, structures and services. It includes planning and execution of the work, protection and support of adjacent structures and removal of demolished material.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0202</ID>
                  <Name>Demolition - interior and alterations</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the demolition and removal of internal building elements and services from within an existing building.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>022</ID>
              <Name>Preparation and groundwork</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>None</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0221</ID>
                  <Name>Site management</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to site preparation requirements including existing services, site clearing, stormwater and sediment control, tree removal/protection/transplanting/maintenance, and temporary landscape fencing.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0222</ID>
                  <Name>Earthwork</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to topsoil removal, excavation, filling and compaction as required for building operations. The worksection contains technical content which must be customised by a professional engineer for inclusion in a project specification.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0223</ID>
                  <Name>Service trenching</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to trenching for underground services within a building site. It covers fill materials, existing services, existing surfaces, excavating, trench back fill and surface restoration.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0224</ID>
                  <Name>Stormwater - site</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to stormwater drainage associated with pavements and other non-building projects. For internal stormwater piping for roof water and for simple external systems related to buildings, use  0821 Stormwater – buildings.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>024</ID>
              <Name>Landscape structures</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>None</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0241</ID>
                  <Name>Landscape - walling and edging</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to retaining and free standing walls subject to height criteria conforming with local authority requirements.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0242</ID>
                  <Name>Landscape - fences and barriers</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to basic fencing including picket and paling (plain paling and lap and cap) fencing, generally for domestic use; chainwire and welded mesh fencing for industrial, commercial and institutional use.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0243</ID>
                  <Name>Landscape - water features</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to self-contained water features in open landscaped areas.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>025</ID>
              <Name>Landscape cultivation</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>None</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0250</ID>
                  <Name>Landscape - gardening</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to simple ‘soft’ landscaping. It has been prepared for and is suitable only for work of a scale or size which does not warrant the use of separate worksections for each of the different aspects of landscaping work. As such, it combines relevant clauses from the following stand-alone landscape worksections: 0222 Earthwork, 0251 Landscape – soils, 0252 Landscape - natural grass surfaces, 0253 Landscape – planting and 0255 Landscape – plant procurement.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0251</ID>
                  <Name>Landscape - soils</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to soils for landscaping including, rock work, filling, topsoil, topsoil additives, compost and mulch. Geotechnical site investigation and soil related earthworks are also covered.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0252</ID>
                  <Name>Landscape - soft surfaces</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to grass seeding, hydroseeding and hydromulching, turfing, stolonising, and temporary grassing.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0253</ID>
                  <Name>Landscape - planting</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to composts, fertilisers, binders, mulching, planting, insect spraying, tree pruning and anchorage and is principally concerned with so-called softworks.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0254</ID>
                  <Name>Irrigation</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to automatically controlled, fixed watering systems. It includes micro irrigation, drip irrigation systems, sub surface irrigation and valve boxes.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0255</ID>
                  <Name>Landscape - plant procurement</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template includes shrubs and ground cover as well as trees. It is structured to allow for the supply of plant material as a separate early contract or as part of the head contract.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0256</ID>
                  <Name>Landscape - establishment</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to landscape establishment and maintenance for the period between the date of practical completion and the date of final completion under the head contract.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0257</ID>
                  <Name>Landscape - road reserve and street trees (AUS-SPEC)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template includes soft landscaping minor works and is applicable to:The vegetation of cut and fill batters, pathway verges, median areas and open drains.Surface preparation, topsoiling, fertilising, and turfing or sowing of seed. It is also suitable for surface protection works, hydroseeding, hydromulching and straw mulching.The supply, planting, fertilising, mulching, staking, watering and maintenance of plants including street trees.Refer to the relevant NATSPEC worksections for major works.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>026</ID>
              <Name>Landscape finishes</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>None</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0261</ID>
                  <Name>Landscape - furniture and fixtures</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the supply and installation of proprietary items associated with landscape works, including shade structures.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>027</ID>
              <Name>Pavements</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>None</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0271</ID>
                  <Name>Pavement base and subbase</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the supply, spreading, compaction and trimming of base and subbase courses of flexible pavements for access or car parking.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0272</ID>
                  <Name>Asphaltic concrete</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the supply and laying of asphalt for ancillary areas not forming public roadways.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0273</ID>
                  <Name>Sprayed bituminous surfacing</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to bituminous sprayed surfacing including priming, primer sealing and resealing of ancillary areas not forming public roadways.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0274</ID>
                  <Name>Concrete pavement</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the supply and placement of concrete for concrete pavements such as loading docks, carparks, landscape hard paving within site boundaries. It includes residential streets, paths and driveways associated with a building project.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0275</ID>
                  <Name>Segmental pavers - mortar bed</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to external paving of clay, stone, industrial cast stone, terrazzo and manufactured cementitious pavers on a cement mortar bed and adhesive bed to concrete substrates.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0276</ID>
                  <Name>Segmental pavers - sand bed</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the supply, placement and compaction of proprietary clay and concrete paving on sand bedding for use in vehicular pavements, cycleways, footpaths and landscaped areas, over unbound base and/or subbase layer/s. This worksection does not apply to public roads and streets.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0277</ID>
                  <Name>Pavement ancillaries</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the installation of channels, kerbs, linemarking and some types of vehicle barriers.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0278</ID>
                  <Name>Granular surfaces</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the construction of granular pathways, driveways and outdoor living areas, and includes subgrade trimming, base compaction, edge restraints and granular surfacing.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>028</ID>
              <Name>Pathways (AUS-SPEC)</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>None</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0281</ID>
                  <Name>Bushfire perimeter tracks</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the construction of perimeter tracks for bushfire protection in rural and urban developments. It addresses requirements for constructing tracks so that soil erosion is minimised and access is maintained under bushfire conditions.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0282</ID>
                  <Name>Pathways and cycleways (Construction)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to construction of pavements for pathways and cycleways. It includes requirements for subgrade preparation and construction of subbase and base for concrete and asphalt pavements.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>029</ID>
              <Name>Retaining walls (AUS-SPEC)</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>None</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0292</ID>
                  <Name>Masonry walls</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the construction of concrete, brick or stone masonry unit retaining walls and free-standing walls such as noise attenuation, dwarf and feature walls for landscaping or similar structure. It includes excavation for footings, construction of reinforced concrete footings, laying of masonry units, placement of subsurface drainage and backfill to the wall.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0293</ID>
                  <Name>Crib retaining walls</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the construction of proprietary timber and precast concrete crib retaining walls for retaining and reinforcing soil, rock and other materials. This may involve design. It includes excavation for foundations, reinforced concrete footing, precast concrete or treated timber crib wall, subsurface drainage and backfilling in and behind the crib wall.</Description>
                  <Availability>None</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
          </Children>
        </Item>
        <Item>
          <ID>03</ID>
          <Name>STRUCTURE</Name>
          <Description/>
          <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
          <Children>
            <Item>
              <ID>030</ID>
              <Name>Foundations</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>301</ID>
                  <Name>Piling</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>031</ID>
              <Name>Concrete</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0310</ID>
                  <Name>Concrete - combined</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the use of concrete for building and associated structures. It is suitable for work of a scale or size which does not need a separate worksection for each of the different parts of the concrete work. It combines relevant clauses from the following worksections: 0311 Concrete formwork, 0312 Concrete reinforcement, 0313 Concrete post-tensioned, 0314 Concrete in situ and 0315 Concrete finishes. For large projects and for projects which include precast and tilt-up concrete, use separate worksections.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0311</ID>
                  <Name>Concrete formwork</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to supply, installation and removal of formwork for concrete work in buildings and associated structures. It includes formwork using profiled sheeting and plywood. This worksection is generally used in conjunction with other concrete worksections.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0312</ID>
                  <Name>Concrete reinforcement</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to supply and installation of fibre and steel reinforcement in concrete for buildings and associated structures. It includes ties, supports and dowelling. This worksection is generally used in conjunction with other concrete worksection.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0313</ID>
                  <Name>Concrete post-tensioned</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to bonded post-tensioning of concrete using strand, bar or wire. It includes concrete elements that are post-tensioned on site as part of the concrete construction process. Cable stays, external post-tensioning and ground anchors are excluded. It anticipates the possibility of contractor design.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0314</ID>
                  <Name>Concrete in situ</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0315</ID>
                  <Name>Concrete finishes</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the production of formed and unformed finishes to concrete surfaces in building and associated structures. It covers the common surface finishes. Project specific finishes may be added, if required. This worksection should be used in conjunction with the concrete in situ worksection, in particular for curing.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0316</ID>
                  <Name>Precast concrete</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0317</ID>
                  <Name>Tilt-up concrete</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0318</ID>
                  <Name>Shotcrete</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to pre-mixed (wet) concrete which is applied pneumatically and compacted dynamically under high velocity. It should be used in situations where formed in situ concrete is not appropriate. This worksection is not applicable to dry mix shotcrete, or mechanically applied shotcrete used for tunnelling and mining ground support applications.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0319</ID>
                  <Name>Minor concrete works (AUS-SPEC)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the supply and placement of concrete, including sprayed concrete for concrete works of an auxiliary/supplementary nature to the primary works taking place. It includes ancillary requirements such as ground preparation, formwork and reinforcement. Auxiliary concrete works include drainage pits and other ancillary drainage structures, headwalls, wingwalls, in-situ box culverts, box culvert base slabs, retaining walls, footings, concrete safety barriers and works of a similar nature.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>032</ID>
              <Name>Earth</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0321</ID>
                  <Name>Monolithic stabilised earth walls</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to precast concrete elements cast in a manufacturing plant or factory, distant from the final installation location and under quality control. Precast elements include reinforced and pre/post tensioned floors, walls, beams and columns. It includes connections, fixings and lifting accessories. Installation and erection procedures are in accordance with the ASCC National code of practice for precast, tilt-up and concrete elements in building construction and AS 3850.2 as required. The worksection permits contractor design. This worksection is endorsed by the National Precast Concrete Association Australia (NPCAA - www.npcaa.com.au).</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0322</ID>
                  <Name>Mud brick walls</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to tilt-up (or tilt-slab) concrete vertical wall elements cast in a horizontal position at or near its final location. It involves installation by rotation about one edge until vertical. The panels must be stabilised by bracing or temporary propping members. This worksection is aligned with AS 3850.1 and AS 3850.2. The worksection permits contractor design.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0323</ID>
                  <Name>Straw bale</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>033</ID>
              <Name>Masonry</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0331</ID>
                  <Name>Brick and block construction</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to internal and external, load bearing and non-load bearing brick and block construction in buildings and associated structures using brick and block masonry units manufactured from clay, calcium silicate, concrete or autoclaved aerated concrete (AAC). It includes details on mortar, reinforcement, ties and other accessories, lintels, damp proofing and flashings.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0332</ID>
                  <Name>Stone masonry</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to natural stone masonry units used in buildings and associated structures. It includes mortar/grout, lintels, wall ties, damp proof courses and flashings and stone foundations. There is no Australian standard for the stone masonry product. However, the design and construction of masonry structures is covered in AS 3700.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0333</ID>
                  <Name>Stone repair</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the cleaning, repair and restoration of existing stone masonry, including stone removal and replacement work. It includes requirements for natural and synthetic stones, mortars, fixings and repointing.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0334</ID>
                  <Name>Block construction</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to internal and external, load bearing and non-load bearing construction in buildings and associated structures using block masonry units manufactured from concrete or autoclaved aerated concrete (AAC). It includes details on mortar, reinforcement, ties and other accessories, lintels, damp proofing and flashings. This worksection is endorsed by the Concrete Masonry Association of Australia (CMAA). See www.cmaa.com.au.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0335</ID>
                  <Name>Brick construction</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to internal and external, load bearing and non-load bearing construction in buildings and associated structures using brick masonry units manufactured from clay, calcium silicate and concrete. It includes wall ties, lintels, mortar, face and cavity work, damp proof courses and flashing.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>034</ID>
              <Name>Steel</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0341</ID>
                  <Name>Structural steel</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to general structural steel framing in buildings, and associated structures. It includes cold-formed purlins and girts used in conjunction with structural steelwork. It covers welding, bolting, surface preparation and treatment of structural steelwork, and architecturally exposed structural steelwork (AESS).</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0342</ID>
                  <Name>Light steel framing</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0343</ID>
                  <Name>Tensioned membrane structures</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0344</ID>
                  <Name>Steel - hot-dip galvanized coatings</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0345</ID>
                  <Name>Steel - protective paint coatings</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to protective paint coating systems for the protection of steel products and structural steelwork against interior and exterior atmospheric corrosion. It addresses surface preparation, preparation assessment and coating application for new and maintenance work.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0346</ID>
                  <Name>Structural fire protection systems</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to fire protection systems for structural building elements where an FRL is required. They can be specified in prescriptive terms or in performance terms. The worksection is based on the BCA deemed-to-satisfy requirements in BCA Spec A2.3.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>038</ID>
              <Name>Timber</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0381</ID>
                  <Name>Structural timber</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to timber building and civil engineering structures or elements for generally commercial, industrial, marine and similar purposes. It includes major beams and columns in residential buildings, timber portal frames and trusses, timber decks, walkways and jetties, pole structures, timber bridges and timber masts, pylons, towers, and similar structures.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0382</ID>
                  <Name>Light timber framing</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is built around the AS 1684 series, as appropriate. It is applicable to light timber framing, bracing and timber trusses in Class 1 and Class 10 buildings as defined by the BCA.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0383</ID>
                  <Name>Sheet flooring and decking</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to external timber, composite or compressed fibre cement decking, and to internal sheet flooring of plywood, particleboard or compressed fibre cement as either platform floors or fitted floors. It assumes the provision of a supporting structure.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
          </Children>
        </Item>
        <Item>
          <ID>04</ID>
          <Name>ENCLOSURE</Name>
          <Description/>
          <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
          <Children>
            <Item>
              <ID>041</ID>
              <Name>Tanking and damp-proofing</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0411</ID>
                  <Name>Waterproofing - external and tanking</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to tanking and external waterproof membrane applications to roofing, balconies, concrete slabs over below ground spaces, planter boxes and tanking generally. It relies on AS 4654.1 and AS 4654.2. It does not include concrete admixtures, penetrating sealers or decorative coatings.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>042</ID>
              <Name>Roofing</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0421</ID>
                  <Name>Roofing - combined</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the provision of roof coverings of profiled and seamed sheet metal, shingles and shakes, slates, tiles, and roof plumbing. It also covers glazed and plastic sheet roofing, skylights, roof hatches, roof windows, roof ventilators and roof plant access.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0423</ID>
                  <Name>Roofing - profiled sheet metal</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the provision of roof coverings of profiled sheet metal and roof plumbing. It also covers glazed and plastic sheet roofing, skylights, roof hatches, roof windows, roof ventilators and roof plant access.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0424</ID>
                  <Name>Roofing - seamed sheet metal</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the provision of roof coverings of seamed sheet metal and roof plumbing. It also covers glazed and plastic sheet roofing, skylights, roof hatches, roof windows, roof ventilators and roof plant access.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0425</ID>
                  <Name>Roofing - shingles and shakes</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the provision of roof coverings of timber shingles and shakes and roof plumbing. It also covers glazed and plastic sheet roofing, skylights, roof hatches, roof windows, roof ventilators and roof plant access.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0426</ID>
                  <Name>Roofing - slate</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the provision of slate roof coverings and roof plumbing. It also covers glazed and plastic sheet roofing, skylights, roof hatches, roof windows, roof ventilators and roof plant access.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0427</ID>
                  <Name>Roofing - tiles</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the provision of roof coverings of cement, terracotta or pressed sheet metal roofing tiles and roof plumbing. It also covers glazed and plastic sheet roofing, skylights, roof hatches, roof windows, roof ventilators and roof plant access.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0428</ID>
                  <Name>Roof glazing</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0429</ID>
                  <Name>Daylighting devices and skylights</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>043</ID>
              <Name>Cladding</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0431</ID>
                  <Name>Cladding - combined</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to lightweight external wall cladding for work of a scale or size which does not warrant the use of separate worksections for each selected cladding type. It combines relevant clauses from the 0434 Cladding – flat sheets and panels, 0435 Cladding – planks and weatherboards and 0436 Cladding – profiled and seamed sheet metal worksections.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0432</ID>
                  <Name>Curtain walls</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to windows and window-and-spandrel assemblies custom-designed to form part, or the whole, of a building facade. It contains detailed performance and testing requirements and has extensive quality control provisions. Contractor design is expected.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0433</ID>
                  <Name>Stone cladding</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to mechanically fixed natural stone or cast stone cladding panels in external or internal applications.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0434</ID>
                  <Name>Cladding - panels</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to lightweight external wall cladding and facing using AAC panels, composite panels, fibre cement, compressed fibre cement, and plastic or plywood flat sheets.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0435</ID>
                  <Name>Cladding - planks</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to lightweight external wall cladding including hardboard and fibre cement planks, and aluminium and timber weatherboards.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0436</ID>
                  <Name>Cladding - profiled sheet metal</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to lightweight external wall cladding of profiled and seamed sheet metal products.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0437</ID>
                  <Name>Cladding - sheet and pre-assembled systems</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0438</ID>
                  <Name>Cement board cladding</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>045</ID>
              <Name>Doors and windows</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0451</ID>
                  <Name>Windows and glazed doors</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to windows and glazed doors consisting of proprietary lines (or suites) of manufactured products, supplied as complete systems, fabricated and assembled to the standard designs of specialist firms in documented materials such as aluminium, steel, timber and plastics. It includes glazing, hardware and associated integral blinds, louvres, and grilles as well as installation accessories, such as fixings, flashings, sealants and seals, caulking and weather-stripping, necessary for the satisfactory functioning of the whole system.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0453</ID>
                  <Name>Doors and access panels</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to conventional door frames of metal and timber with door leaves of timber and various timber and plastic products. This worksection only covers some key generic requirements as the range of available products, performance requirements and design choices is so wide.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0454</ID>
                  <Name>Overhead doors</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to sectional and tilting overhead doors, roller shutters (including fire shutters), grilles and garage doors. Manual and motorised operation are covered.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0455</ID>
                  <Name>Door hardware</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to hardware items such as hinges, keys, locks, latches, furniture and door controllers including automated devices and provides two alternative types of schedules for specifying these items – selection schedules and door-by-door schedules.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0456</ID>
                  <Name>Louvre windows</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to louvre windows consisting of proprietary products, supplied as complete systems fabricated and assembled by specialist firms to their standard designs. Components include glass, metal, timber or plastic louvre blades, hardware and associated screens and grilles, as well as installation accessories, such as fixings, flashings, sealants, caulking and weather-stripping, necessary for the satisfactory functioning of the whole system.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0457</ID>
                  <Name>External screens</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to external screens consisting of proprietary lines (or suites) of manufactured products, supplied as complete systems fabricated and assembled by specialist firms to their standard designs, in materials such as aluminium, steel and stainless steel. It includes sunscreens, trafficable sunscreens, external louvres and blinds, shutters, awnings and pergolas fixed to building facades or openings to control sunlight and/or to provide privacy, to screen plant and equipment, or to provide an architectural feature. It applies to fixed, adjustable, operable and automatically controlled types.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>046</ID>
              <Name>Glass</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0461</ID>
                  <Name>Glazing</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to glazing in framed openings to windows, doors and curtain walls based on AS 1288.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0462</ID>
                  <Name>Structural glazing</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the installation of the following structural glazing systems:Structural silicone glazing in which the glass is adhered to the framing system with a structural sealant.Framed, unframed and partly framed glass assemblies including faceted glazing, fin supported glazing, patch plate jointed suspended glazing and point fixed glazing incorporating spider type glass fittings.Suspended frameless glass assembly with wind stiffening systems.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0463</ID>
                  <Name>Glass blockwork</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to fully framed glass blockwork with mortar joints.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0467</ID>
                  <Name>Glass components</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to glass products such as shower screens, balustrades and mirrors.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>047</ID>
              <Name>Insulation</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0471</ID>
                  <Name>Insulation and pliable membranes</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to insulation and pliable membranes for floors, walls, ceilings and roofs. It generally relies on AS 3999, AS/NZS 4200.1, AS 4200.2 and AS/NZS 4859.1. A pliable building membrane may be installed to act as a sarking membrane, vapour barrier, thermal insulation or any combination of the three. This worksection does not cover insulation for services (e.g. for ductwork, 0744 Ductwork insulation).</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0472</ID>
                  <Name>Acoustic insulation</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to acoustic insulation for floors, walls and ceilings to reduce the transmission of airborne and impact sound between individual rooms. It includes plenum baffles and flanking sound insulation.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0473</ID>
                  <Name>Acoustic floor underlays</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
          </Children>
        </Item>
        <Item>
          <ID>05</ID>
          <Name>INTERIOR</Name>
          <Description/>
          <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
          <Children>
            <Item>
              <ID>051</ID>
              <Name>Lining</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0511</ID>
                  <Name>Lining</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the installation of internal lining systems permanently fixed to walls and ceilings. It deals with internal dry linings of timber boards, gypsum plasterboard and cellulose fibre reinforced cement.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>052</ID>
              <Name>Partitions</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0521</ID>
                  <Name>Partitions - demountable</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to proprietary demountable partition systems.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0522</ID>
                  <Name>Partitions - framed and lined</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to internal framed and lined partitions with either lightweight steel or timber framing and plasterboard or fibre cement lining; and with bulk acoustic insulation, or autoclaved aerated concrete panels.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0523</ID>
                  <Name>Partitions - brick and block</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to internal non-load bearing brick and block construction of a simple nature associated with interior fitout works.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0524</ID>
                  <Name>Partitions - glazed</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to internal non-load bearing framed and frameless glass partitions, and glazed doors.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0525</ID>
                  <Name>Cubicle systems</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to partitioned cubicles for toilets and showers. The material can be adapted for changing areas and various decontamination cubicles such as air showers.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0526</ID>
                  <Name>Terrazzo  precast</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to precast units and assemblies including toilet and shower cubicle partitions, stair units, joinery units, door thresholds and window sills.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0527</ID>
                  <Name>Room dividers</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to operable walls, folding doors and accordion doors.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>053</ID>
              <Name>Ceilings</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0531</ID>
                  <Name>Suspended ceilings - combined</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to flush lined and proprietary ceiling units to  suspended internal ceilings and external soffits of dry construction with suspension systems attached to a supporting structure.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0532</ID>
                  <Name>Suspended ceilings - flush lined</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the fixing of flush lined internal suspended ceilings and external soffits of dry construction with suspension systems attached to a supporting structure.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0533</ID>
                  <Name>Suspended ceilings - ceiling units</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the installation of proprietary ceiling units to suspension systems attached to a supporting structure.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>054</ID>
              <Name>Access floors</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0541</ID>
                  <Name>Access floors</Name>
                  <Description> This worksection Template is applicable to pedestal access floor systems.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>055</ID>
              <Name>Fixtures</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0551</ID>
                  <Name>Joinery</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the shop fabrication and site installation of custom made joinery fixtures and trim to walls and openings.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0552</ID>
                  <Name>Metalwork - fabricated</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to what is generally known as custom built architectural metalwork such as stairs, ladders, walkways, balustrades, handrails, screens, grilles, guards, bollards, furniture, and decorative items.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0553</ID>
                  <Name>Stainless steel benching</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to stainless steel benches and associated fitments usually for commercial applications such as kitchens, laboratories and hospitals.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0554</ID>
                  <Name>Stairs, ladders, walkways and guardrails</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>057</ID>
              <Name>Furnitures and fixtures</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0571</ID>
                  <Name>Workstations</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the supply and installation of office workstations.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0572</ID>
                  <Name>Miscellaneous furniture</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the supply and installation of loose furniture and fixed items that are capable of retrofit.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0573</ID>
                  <Name>Extinguishers and blankets</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to fire extinguishers and fire blankets. Products used must be identified in ActivFire Register of Fire Protection Equipment. The specification should reflect any extra requirements of local statutory authorities. The principal product standards are the AS/NZS 1841 series and AS 2444, a deemed-to-safely standard under the BCA.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0574</ID>
                  <Name>Window coverings</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to window coverings for interior use, both decorative and blockout comprising curtains and blinds, manual and power operated.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0575</ID>
                  <Name>Tapestries</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to wall-hung tapestries woven using the Gobelin method. It was developed in conjunction with the Australian Tapestry Workshop (ATW, formerly the Victorian Tapestry Workshop). There is no central standard.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>058</ID>
              <Name>Signs and features</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0581</ID>
                  <Name>Signs and display</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to house signage, display and statutory signs. Signage for switchboards, piping, etc. should be dealt with in the appropriate technical worksection, but coordinated with this worksection.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
          </Children>
        </Item>
        <Item>
          <ID>06</ID>
          <Name>FINISH</Name>
          <Description/>
          <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
          <Children>
            <Item>
              <ID>061</ID>
              <Name>Trowelled and sprayed coatings</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0611</ID>
                  <Name>Rendering and plastering</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to traditional wet plastering and rendering, though proprietary and special systems may feature in the project specifications and drawings. It includes work on lath, and on panelling of various materials.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0612</ID>
                  <Name>Cementitious toppings</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to cement-based toppings on floors and steps. There is no relevant standard in Australia but there are numerous guides available from BRANZ and the Cement and Concrete Association.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0613</ID>
                  <Name>Terrazzo in situ</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to in situ cementitious terrazzo floor systems. There is no relevant standard.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>062</ID>
              <Name>Wet areas</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0621</ID>
                  <Name>Waterproofing - wet areas</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to waterproof membrane applications to wet areas and is written with reference to AS 3740 and AS/NZS 4858. It includes wet area membranes that are polyester or polyurethane, bituminous, acrylic systems and fibreglass reinforcement.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>063</ID>
              <Name>Tiling</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0631</ID>
                  <Name>Ceramic tiling</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to floor and wall ceramic tiling. Tiles may be specified by manufacturer’s brand name or by generic type, and essential characteristics such as size, colour, surface, edge type. Bedding, grouting, fixing and jointing requirements should also be specified.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0632</ID>
                  <Name>Stone and terrazzo tiling</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to stone tiling, industrial cast stone tiling, terrazzo tiling (cementitious and resinous) and manufactured cementitious tiling on various substrates.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>064</ID>
              <Name>Wall surfacing</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0641</ID>
                  <Name>Applied wall finishes</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to interior decorative wall finishes fixed using wet methods (adhesive/mortar fixed) or dry methods (framed/mechanical systems). It also includes decorative acoustic wall panels.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>065</ID>
              <Name>Floor surfacing</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0651</ID>
                  <Name>Resilient finishes</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to resilient sheet and tile finishes with associated underlay including cork tiles, linoleum, corklinoleum, rubber, polyvinyl chloride (PVC), flexible terrazzo tiles and static control flooring. It also includes synthetic sporting surfaces.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0652</ID>
                  <Name>Carpets</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to carpet materials, including broadloom carpet, carpet tiles, mats and underlays, adhesives, tapes and accessories, their fixing methods and cleaning.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0654</ID>
                  <Name>Engineered panel flooring</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to manufactured floating and adhesive fixed panel floor systems on various subfloors and to sprung timber floors. It assumes the provision of a supporting subfloor or structure.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0655</ID>
                  <Name>Timber flooring</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0656</ID>
                  <Name>Floor sanding and finishing</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to basic floor sanding of timber substrates for other finishes, basic floor sanding as the first stage preparation for clear coating systems, finish sanding for clear coating systems and the selection and application of clear coating systems.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0657</ID>
                  <Name>Resin based seamless flooring</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to resin based flooring including epoxy, polyurethane and methacrylate resins. It also includes in situ resinous terrazzo flooring.This worksection Template is applicable to resin based flooring including epoxy, polyurethane and methacrylate resins.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>067</ID>
              <Name>Painting and wall papering</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0671</ID>
                  <Name>Painting</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the in situ application of coating films to buildings and interior elements. The primary referenced standard is AS/NZS 2311, a guide to products and procedures for the painting of buildings for domestic, commercial and industrial use.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0672</ID>
                  <Name>Textured and membrane coatings</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the in situ application of latex extensible (membrane) coating and textured surface coating systems to buildings and interior elements. The primary referenced standard is AS/NZS 2311 which provides a guide to products and procedures for the painting of buildings for general domestic, commercial and industrial use.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0673</ID>
                  <Name>Powder coatings</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the off-site application of powder coating systems for architectural applications, and to exterior and interior buildings elements. The primary referenced standards are AS 3715 for aluminium and aluminium alloy substrates and AS 4506 for metal substrates, other than aluminium.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0679</ID>
                  <Name>Wall papering</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
          </Children>
        </Item>
        <Item>
          <ID>07</ID>
          <Name>MECHANICAL</Name>
          <Description/>
          <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
          <Children>
            <Item>
              <ID>070</ID>
              <Name>Mechanical general</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0700r</ID>
                  <Name>Reference - Mechanical services</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0700s</ID>
                  <Name>Schedules - Mechanical services</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0701</ID>
                  <Name>Mechanical systems</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template covers mechanical services systems, performance requirements and standards. It includes a summary of the systems, design parameters relating to the mechanical systems and details common to more than one mechanical worksection.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0702</ID>
                  <Name>Mechanical design and install</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to simple mechanical installations for which the specification will be prepared by the architect because the principal has not engaged a specialist mechanical consultant; the mechanical design will be done by the contractor. It deals with packaged air conditioning systems (ducted and non-ducted) and straightforward mechanical ventilation.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0703</ID>
                  <Name>Mechanical design and construct (Design)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the design component of mechanical services projects in which the design will be undertaken by the mechanical contractor. It covers the design process relating to design and construct with the design parameters covered in the respective worksections.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>071</ID>
              <Name>Water plant</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0711</ID>
                  <Name>Chillers - combined</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to factory assembled proprietary electric motor driven reciprocating, centrifugal, screw and scroll chiller sets including air cooled and water cooled, conventional and heat recovery types.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0712</ID>
                  <Name>Water heating boilers</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to boilers not intended to produce steam, in which water is heated to less than its normal atmospheric boiling temperature and consequently do not meet the definition of a boiler in the BCA and AS/NZS 1200. Water heating boilers are used in space heating systems, indirect potable heated water and similar applications.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0713</ID>
                  <Name>Cooling towers</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to cooling towers normally used in commercial buildings. It is not intended for large specialised towers for heavy industrial plant. Evaporative condensers and closed circuit fluid coolers are included in this worksection and fall within the meaning of cooling tower as defined in AS/NZS 3666.1.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0714</ID>
                  <Name>Mechanical pumps</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to end-suction centrifugal, inline circulating and submersible pumps. There are no comprehensive reference standards.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0715</ID>
                  <Name>Tanks, vessels and heat exchangers</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to pressurised vessels and non-pressurised tanks and water to water plate heat exchangers. It includes head tanks (open and closed), water storage tanks for chilled and heating water, calorifiers and ice tanks.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0716</ID>
                  <Name>Chillers - centrifugal</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to factory assembled proprietary electric motor driven water cooled centrifugal chiller sets.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0717</ID>
                  <Name>Chillers - water cooled screw</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to factory assembled proprietary electric motor driven water cooled chiller sets with screw compressors.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0718</ID>
                  <Name>Chillers - air cooled screw and scroll</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to factory assembled proprietary electric motor driven air cooled chiller sets with screw or scroll compressors.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0719</ID>
                  <Name>Chillers - absorption</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to factory assembled proprietary single stage and two stage, water cooled, lithium bromide absorption chillers. This worksection is oriented to absorption chillers as part of systems which typically use relatively low temperature hot water as a heat source.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>072</ID>
              <Name>Air plant</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0721</ID>
                  <Name>Packaged air conditioning</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to one piece and split, direct expansion (DX) packaged air conditioning plant with nominal cooling capacities greater than 8 kW(r). It includes air cooled and water cooled types, and variable refrigerant flow (VRF) systems as well as close control packaged plant.This worksection Template is applicable to one piece and split, direct expansion (DX) packaged air conditioning plant with nominal cooling capacities greater than 8 kW(r). It includes air cooled and variable refrigerant flow (VRF) systems.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0722</ID>
                  <Name>Room air conditioners</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to one piece and split direct expansion (DX), air cooled room air conditioning plant with nominal cooling capacities less than 8 kW(r).</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0723</ID>
                  <Name>Evaporative air coolers</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to proprietary, non-refrigerated evaporative air coolers intended for ducted and free discharge applications. The reference standard is AS 2913.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0724</ID>
                  <Name>Air handling plant - combined</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to all types of air handling plant from small room fan coil units to large built-up air handlers. It deals with proprietary air handling plant, site erected air handling units and site erected plenums associated with proprietary air handling plant.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0725</ID>
                  <Name>Air handling plant - built up</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to site erected air handling units and site erected plenums.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0726</ID>
                  <Name>Air handling plant - minor</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to small room fan coil units.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0727</ID>
                  <Name>Air handling plant - packaged</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to proprietary factory assembled air handling plant and includes site erected plenums associated with these.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>073</ID>
              <Name>Air handling components</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0731</ID>
                  <Name>Fans</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to centrifugal, axial flow, mixed flow and propeller fans, roof mounted fans and window/wall mounted fans of the type commonly used in air conditioning and ventilation systems.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0732</ID>
                  <Name>Air filters</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to air filters commonly used in mechanical systems. It includes dry media dust filters (including HEPA, viscous impingement and electrostatic), grease filters and gas phase absorbers (e.g. activated carbon). It is based on AS 1324.1, AS 1324.2 (general air conditioning filters) and AS 4260 (HEPA and MEPA types).This worksection Template is applicable to air filters commonly used in mechanical systems. It includes dry media dust filters (including viscous impingement), grease filters. It is based on AS 1324.1, AS 1324.2 (general air conditioning filters).</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0733</ID>
                  <Name>Air coils</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to coils used in heating and cooling systems and includes water, steam and refrigerant coils.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0734</ID>
                  <Name>Humidifiers</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to proprietary self-generating electric steam humidifiers that produce steam at atmospheric pressure. It may also be applied to humidifiers in packaged computer room air conditioning units. It does not apply to humidifiers that use a boiler as defined in AS 1228.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>074</ID>
              <Name>Ductwork and components</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0741</ID>
                  <Name>Ductwork</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to ductwork fabricated from galvanised steel, stainless steel and aluminium. It includes ductwork ancillaries such as flexible duct, duct fire-resistance level, dampers, fabricated hoods and canopies. The reference standards are AS 4254.1 (flexible duct) and AS 4254.2 (rigid duct). PVC-U ductwork, which is not covered by AS 4254.2, is also included.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0744</ID>
                  <Name>Ductwork insulation</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to acoustic and thermal insulation and sheathing of ductwork. Insulating materials include glass wool, rock wool, polyester fibre, polyolefin foam and elastomeric foam. Facing materials include aluminium foil laminate and sheet metal. The worksection references AS 4254.1 and AS 4254.2.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0745</ID>
                  <Name>Attenuators and acoustic louvres</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to duct mounted sound attenuators, wall mounted acoustic louvres and cross-talk attenuators.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0746</ID>
                  <Name>Air grilles</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to fixed and adjustable air grilles, used in air conditioning and ventilation systems. The term air grille is used generically and includes diffusers, registers and weatherproof (exterior) louvres. The reference standard is AS 4254.2.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0747</ID>
                  <Name>Variable air volume  terminals</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to variable air volume (VAV) terminals (also called VAV boxes). It covers series and parallel fan assisted types and non-fan, pressure independent terminals. Also included are hot water and electric heating associated with VAV terminals.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0748</ID>
                  <Name>Chilled beams</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to chilled beam terminals. It covers active and passive type terminals.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>075</ID>
              <Name>Piping</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0751</ID>
                  <Name>Mechanical piping</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to piping, valves, fittings and accessories commonly used for mechanical systems including chilled, condenser and heating water, steam, condensate, and liquid fuels. It covers piping in a variety of materials including steel, copper and plastic, and includes valves, fittings, supports, and accessories. The worksection is based on AS 4041. The worksection also covers strainers and isolating, non-return, throttling, level control, pressure relief, air relief, and pressure-reducing valves. It does not include thermostatic, solenoid, motorised modulating, or refrigerant valves.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0752</ID>
                  <Name>Mechanical piping insulation</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the insulation and sheathing of piping, tanks, vessels and flues. It covers a variety of materials including FBS-1 Glass Wool and rock wool, polyester, polyolefin, polystyrene foam and elastomeric foam.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0753</ID>
                  <Name>Water treatment</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to water treatment for open and closed water systems and is intended for use in conjunction with AS/NZS 3666.1. The clauses for sand filters and water softener may be used for boiler feed water treatment. Cathodic protection for condenser water systems by impressed current and sacrificial anodes are also included.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0754</ID>
                  <Name>Liquid fuels</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to fuel oil systems. It is intended for use in conjunction with AS 1940 which sets out the requirements and recommendations for the storage and handling of flammable and combustible liquids. The worksection covers components normally used in a fuel oil system including the storage tanks, pumps, piping, valves and accessories.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0755</ID>
                  <Name>Medical gas systems</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template covers non-flammable medical gas systems including medical breathing air, medical suction, oxygen, nitrous oxide, surgical tool gas and carbon dioxide. The reference standard is AS 2896. There are many instances where AS 2896 includes recommendations that are not Normative (e.g. expressed as should rather than shall). This worksection includes text to mandate these instances.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>076</ID>
              <Name>Refrigeration</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0761</ID>
                  <Name>Refrigeration</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to built-up refrigeration systems. It is intended for use in conjunction with AS/NZS 5149.1, AS/NZS 5149.2, AS/NZS 5149.3 and AS/NZS 5149.4. It covers refrigeration equipment and components including piping, accessories, evaporators, condensers and compressors.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0762</ID>
                  <Name>Cool rooms</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to refrigerated cool rooms with a room operating temperature below 5°C including those operating below freezing. It includes the construction of the room and its associated refrigeration system and controls.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>077</ID>
              <Name>Control</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0771</ID>
                  <Name>Automatic controls</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to large automatic control systems for mechanical services and includes hardware, software and cabling material. If used in conjunction with 0773 Building management systems and related worksections, it can provide a complete building management system (BMS) for building management, monitoring and control.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0772</ID>
                  <Name>Automatic controls - minor</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to large automatic control systems for mechanical services and includes hardware, software and cabling material. If used in conjunction with 0773 Building management systems and related worksections, it can provide a complete building management system (BMS) for building management, monitoring and control.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0773</ID>
                  <Name>Building management systems</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to Building Management Systems (BMS) which provide the facility to monitor, control and manage building services systems which may include mechanical services, power systems, lighting, fire detection and alarms, electronic security, hydraulic services and medical gas services. BMS operates through a system of discrete stand-alone controllers which are networked together using a common, open, communications protocol.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>078</ID>
              <Name>Mechanical electrical</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0781</ID>
                  <Name>Mechanical electrical</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to electrical work associated with medium to large mechanical projects where the specification and selections will be prepared by a mechanical engineer.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0782</ID>
                  <Name>Mechanical electrical - minor</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the electrical work associated with minor mechanical projects using packaged plant and smaller ventilation systems. It is a simplified design and install type specification without selection schedules.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0784</ID>
                  <Name>Motors and starters</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to alternating current electric motors, their starters and associated motor protection equipment. It includes a range of starter types including direct-on-line, star delta, semi-conductor and variable speed drives.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>079</ID>
              <Name>Mechanical commissioning and maintenance</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0791</ID>
                  <Name>Mechanical commissioning</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to balancing, commissioning and testing of mechanical services including control systems. This worksection is written on the basis that a Commissioning Authority has not been engaged. If the principal requires a Commissioning Authority to oversee a commissioning process for the whole of the project, the worksection will require amendment under Commissioning Authority’s direction. Use the Commissioning worksection in conjunction with this and other worksections to document the commissioning process on a project-wide basis.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0792</ID>
                  <Name>Mechanical maintenance</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to periodic and statutory maintenance and emergency repairs of mechanical services systems during the defects liability period including plant, distribution systems, automatic controls and mechanical electrical installations. It can also be used to document requirements for maintenance contracts for existing buildings. It relies on there being an operations and maintenance manual for the building.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
          </Children>
        </Item>
        <Item>
          <ID>08</ID>
          <Name>HYDRAULIC</Name>
          <Description/>
          <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
          <Children>
            <Item>
              <ID>080</ID>
              <Name>Hydraulic general</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0800r</ID>
                  <Name>Reference - Hydraulic services</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0800s</ID>
                  <Name>Schedules - Hydraulic services</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0801</ID>
                  <Name>Hydraulic systems</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template covers hydraulic services systems, performance requirements and standards. It includes a summary of the systems, design parameters relating to the hydraulic systems and details common to more than one hydraulic worksection.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0802</ID>
                  <Name>Hydraulic design and install</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to simple hydraulic installations for which the specification will be prepared by the architect because the principal has not engaged a specialist hydraulic consultant, the hydraulic design will be done by the contractor. It deals with hot and cold water services, sanitary plumbing and drainage, stormwater, rainwater storage systems, grey water systems, natural gas, LP gas and fire services installations.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>081</ID>
              <Name>Hydraulic components</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0811</ID>
                  <Name>Sanitary fixtures</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the selection and installation of sanitary fixtures. It incorporates design for access and mobility standards AS 1428.1 and AS 1428.2 as well as the standards listed in the WaterMark Product Database.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0812</ID>
                  <Name>Tapware</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to taps and tapware and includes related fittings such as towel rails and grab rails.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0813</ID>
                  <Name>Water heaters</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to storage type water heaters and covers electric, gas, solar (with gas or electric boost) and heat pump types. It also includes small instantaneous water heaters. The reference standards are the AS/NZS 3500 series which are cited in the PCA.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0814</ID>
                  <Name>Hydraulic pumps</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to pumps used in hot and cold water services and stormwater. The pumps in this worksection are all close-coupled type (i.e. they have no pump bearings). For direct-coupled pumps refer to the 0714 Mechanical pumps worksection.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0815</ID>
                  <Name>Boiling, chilled, and filtered water dispenser</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to boiling, chilled and filtered water dispenser systems.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>082</ID>
              <Name>Hydraulic systems</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0821</ID>
                  <Name>Stormwater - buildings</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to stormwater systems related to buildings including internal stormwater piping for roof water and simple external systems. For stormwater drainage associated with pavements and other non-building projects normally designed by a civil engineer, use  0224 Stormwater – site.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0822</ID>
                  <Name>Wastewater</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to sanitary plumbing (above ground) and sanitary drainage (below ground) for a range of applications including laboratories. On-site treatment is limited to septic tanks.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0823</ID>
                  <Name>Cold and heated water</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to potable cold and heated (hot and warm) water services including water for human consumption, food preparation, food utensil washing and personal hygiene. It is also applicable in certain circumstances to non-potable water services.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0824</ID>
                  <Name>Fuel gas</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to installations for natural gas and other fuel gases such as liquid petroleum gas (LPG), tempered liquid petroleum gas (TLP) and simulated natural gas (SNG). The worksection does not cover appliances. The reference standard for this worksection is AS/NZS 5601.1. Liquefied natural gas (LNG) facilities are outside the scope of this worksection.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0825</ID>
                  <Name>Rainwater storage systems</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to rainwater storage systems and ancillaries. It covers rigid plastic, bladder, coated steel and concrete tanks for above ground and underground installation.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0826</ID>
                  <Name>Greywater systems</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to systems and ancillaries for greywater (water from hand basins, showers, washing machines and the like not containing human excrement). The worksection covers both untreated (greywater diversion systems) and treated greywater systems.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>083</ID>
              <Name>Fire systems</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0831</ID>
                  <Name>Hydrants</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to fire hydrant installations, accessories, piping and installation either mandated by the BCA or required for other reasons. The worksection relies almost entirely on the referenced standards, many of which are statutory.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0832</ID>
                  <Name>Hose reels</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to fire hose reels. It relies almost entirely on the referenced standards, many of which are statutory. For installation, AS 2441 (Installation of fire hose reels) is a deemed-to-satisfy standard under the BCA.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0833</ID>
                  <Name>Sprinklers</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to automatic fire sprinkler systems conforming to the AS 2118 series. It may be used for both standard fire sprinkler systems and wall wetting sprinkler (drencher) systems. Products used must be on the ActivFire Register of Fire Protection Equipment.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>088</ID>
              <Name>Hydraulic electrical</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0882</ID>
                  <Name>Hydraulic electrical - minor</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the electrical work associated with minor mechanical projects using packaged plant and smaller ventilation systems. It is a simplified design and install type specification without selection schedules.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>089</ID>
              <Name>Hydraulic commissioning and maintenance</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0891</ID>
                  <Name>Hydraulic maintenance</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to periodic and statutory maintenance and emergency repairs of hydraulic plant and reticulation systems during the defects liability period. It can also be used to document requirements for maintenance contracts for existing buildings. It relies on there being an operations and maintenance manual for the building.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
          </Children>
        </Item>
        <Item>
          <ID>09</ID>
          <Name>ELECTRICAL</Name>
          <Description/>
          <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
          <Children>
            <Item>
              <ID>090</ID>
              <Name>Electrical general</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0900r</ID>
                  <Name>Reference - Electrical services</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0900s</ID>
                  <Name>Schedules - Electrical services</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0901</ID>
                  <Name>Electrical systems</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template covers electrical services systems, performance requirements and standards. It includes a summary of the systems, design parameters relating to the electrical systems and details, common to more than one electrical worksection.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0902</ID>
                  <Name>Electrical design and install</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to simple electrical services installations, in which the specification will be prepared by the architect, without the involvement of a specialist electrical consultant, and the electrical design will be undertaken by the contractor. It includes a summary of the systems and design parameters relating to the electrical installation.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>091</ID>
              <Name>Electrical equipment</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0911</ID>
                  <Name>Cable support and duct systems</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to cable support and duct systems that are common to a number of worksections such as 0921 Low voltage power systems and 0961 Telecommunications cabling. These include metallic and non-metallic conduits, cable trays and ladders. This worksection includes systems for use both within buildings and externally.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>092</ID>
              <Name>Power systems</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0921</ID>
                  <Name>Low voltage power systems</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the provision of low voltage power systems, associated low voltage power cables and conductors, and connected outlets and accessories.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>093</ID>
              <Name>Power supply equipment</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0931</ID>
                  <Name>Power generation - engine driven</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the provision of proprietary packaged generating sets powered by reciprocating diesel or gas engines, and includes controls and ancillary equipment. They may be self-contained, enclosed external units, or installed singly or in groups inside a building.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0933</ID>
                  <Name>Power generation - photovoltaic</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the provision of photovoltaic generating systems incorporating storage batteries, inverter, protection, controls and ancillary equipment. It may be used for grid connected or stand-alone systems.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0937</ID>
                  <Name>Uninterruptible power supply</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to battery driven, static uninterruptible power supplies (UPSs) designed to provide an instantaneous, short term 50 Hz power supply in the event of interruption to the normal power supply. It is not intended for direct grid connection.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>094</ID>
              <Name>Power distribution equipment</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0941</ID>
                  <Name>Switchboards - proprietary</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to proprietary, off-the-shelf low voltage distribution switchboards using standard proprietary components and relies on AS/NZS 3000, AS/NZS 3439 series and AS/NZS 61439. It should be used in conjunction with the 0943 Switchboard components worksection.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0942</ID>
                  <Name>Switchboards - custom-built</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to custom-built, low voltage switchboards. It should be used in conjunction with the 0943 Switchboard components worksection. This worksection provides a brief specification for the design, manufacture, installation and testing of low voltage custom-built switchboards. It relies on AS/NZS 3000, AS/NZS 3439.1 and AS/NZS 61439.1 as well as individual standards related to various components.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0943</ID>
                  <Name>Switchboard components</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to protective and control devices and for the selection of switchboard components.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0947</ID>
                  <Name>Power factor correction</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to microprocessor controlled power factor correction equipment.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>095</ID>
              <Name>Lighting systems</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0951</ID>
                  <Name>Lighting</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the components of the lighting system and includes proprietary (and refurbished proprietary) luminaires, lighting control systems and wiring requirements.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>096</ID>
              <Name>Communication systems</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0961</ID>
                  <Name>Telecommunications cabling</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the provision of a telecommunications cabling network in commercial (non-industrial) buildings and relies on the Australian Communications and Media Authority (ACMA) technical standards AS/CA S008 and AS/CA S009. This worksection supplements the ACMA standards, and provides a general specification for a complete telecommunications block cabling and facility wiring system, including connection frames.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0962</ID>
                  <Name>Television distribution systems</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the provision of RF analog and digital television and sound system distribution systems and relies on AS/NZS 1367. The worksection is intended to supplement this standard and provide a general specification for commercial quality systems that would be installed in residential and commercial buildings. This includes the reception of broadcast band FM radio signals, analog and digital free-to-air television, and cable and satellite television broadcasts.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0963</ID>
                  <Name>Sound systems</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to systems used for medium quality sound reinforcement for public address across campuses and sites and in simple halls and lecture theatres. It also includes the necessary provisions to comply with the BCA requirements for the hearing impaired.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>097</ID>
              <Name>Safety systems</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0971</ID>
                  <Name>Emergency evacuation lighting</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the provision of emergency evacuation lighting and exit signs in buildings. It relies on AS 2293. It is expected that the emergency lighting system has been designed and luminaires selected that meet the project requirements for lighting performance and electrical characteristics.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0972</ID>
                  <Name>Fire detection and alarms</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to fire detection and alarm systems in buildings connected to a remote monitoring network. It covers associated equipment, such as door holders, and the connection to air handling systems where required. Also covered are addressable detector systems, where a data cable loop can be used to connect a mixture of thermal and combustion product detectors, to a common zone.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0973</ID>
                  <Name>Emergency warning and intercommunication</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the provision of building emergency warning and intercommunication systems (EWIS) and relies on AS 1670.4, AS 60849 and AS 4428.4. It is also to be used for occupant warning systems (OWS) which are a requirement of the BCA wherever a fire alarm system is included.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0979</ID>
                  <Name>Lightning protection</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the provision of lightning protection systems to achieve a tolerable level of risk for buildings. It relies on AS/NZS 1768 and assumes a system is required, following an assessment of risk or regardless of any risk assessment, when there is a desire to eliminate avoidable risk.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>098</ID>
              <Name>Security systems</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0981</ID>
                  <Name>Electronic security</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the provision of access control and security alarm systems in buildings. It relies generally on AS 2201, and includes local alarm systems, centrally monitored systems, access control systems and closed circuit television (CCTV). The worksection is intended to supplement the standard and to cover general commercial grade systems, of the sort likely to be installed in office buildings, residential apartments, hospitals, nursing homes and similar buildings. The worksection can also be used for institutional projects such as schools and technical colleges by the inclusion of appropriate details in the project specification.See NATSPEC TECHreport TR 05 Selection and design of BUILDING IT systems for an overview of IT systems required for buildings, how different IT system components are provided and the interrelationship of the relevant NATSPEC worksections.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>099</ID>
              <Name>Electrical commissioning and maintenance</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>0991</ID>
                  <Name>Electrical maintenance</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to periodic and statutory maintenance and emergency repairs of electrical services systems, during the defects liability period. It can also be used to document requirements for maintenance contracts for existing buildings. It relies on an there being an operations and maintenance manual for the building.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
          </Children>
        </Item>
        <Item>
          <ID>10</ID>
          <Name>CONVEYING</Name>
          <Description/>
          <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
          <Children>
            <Item>
              <ID>100</ID>
              <Name>Conveying general</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children/>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>101</ID>
              <Name>Conveying equipment</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1011</ID>
                  <Name>Lifts</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to passenger lifts for use in buildings, other than private residences, up to four storeys. As a performance based (design and construct) worksection, it is intended for use if no specialist lift consultant is engaged.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1012</ID>
                  <Name>Escalators and moving walkways</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>102</ID>
              <Name>Other conveying equipment</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children/>
            </Item>
          </Children>
        </Item>
        <Item>
          <ID>11</ID>
          <Name>CONSTRUCTION - ROADWAYS (AUS-SPEC)</Name>
          <Description/>
          <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
          <Children>
            <Item>
              <ID>110</ID>
              <Name>General</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1101</ID>
                  <Name>Control of traffic</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the management of temporary traffic movement for safe negotiation of work sites on roads and adjacent to roadways. It includes:The design, construction, maintenance and removal of temporary roadways including side tracks, divided road crossovers and detours. This may include control of erosion and sedimentation, clearing and grubbing, earthworks and drainage works.The provision of traffic controllers, signposting, road markings, raised pavement markers, lights and safety barriers.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1102</ID>
                  <Name>Control of erosion and sedimentation (Construction)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the control of erosion and sedimentation in conformance with an approved Erosion and sediment control plan (ESCP). It provides for either documentation of requirements for control plans prepared by the contractor or documentation of control measures by principal/consultant. It includes both temporary and permanent erosion and sediment control measures.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>111</ID>
              <Name>Formation preparation</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1111</ID>
                  <Name>Clearing and grubbing</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the clearing, grubbing and removal of all vegetation, logs, stumps, boulders, roots, scrub, debris and dumped material for site works for roadway construction. The work also includes removal of all rubbish and other materials that are unsuitable for use in the works, and demolition and disposal of any minor built structures.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1112</ID>
                  <Name>Earthworks (Roadways)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the excavation, removal of topsoil, cuttings, and construction of batters and embankments. It also includes compaction and moisture requirements, fill construction, borrow activities and selected material zone.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1113</ID>
                  <Name>Stabilisation</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to materials and processes for stabilisation of subgrade and pavement courses. Stabilisation binders include cement, quicklime, hydrated lime, cementitious blends, bitumen emulsion, foamed bitumen, granular materials and dry powdered polymer.This worksection should be reviewed by a professional engineer and amended if necessary to suit local conditions.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>112</ID>
              <Name>Rainwater collection</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1121</ID>
                  <Name>Open drains , including kerb and channel (gutter)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the construction, lining and protection of all types of open drains, including unlined and lined open drains.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1122</ID>
                  <Name>Kerb and channel (gutter) replacement</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the construction of new kerbs and channels (gutters) and associated works including foundations for components, adjustment/replacement of gully pits and reinstatement of pavement and driveways, as documented. It also includes the removal and disposal of existing kerbs and channels (gutters).</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>113</ID>
              <Name>Rigid pavements</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1131</ID>
                  <Name>Rolled concrete subbase</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to construction of roller compacted concrete subbase. It includes mixing, transportation, placement, compaction, jointing and curing.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1132</ID>
                  <Name>Lean mix concrete subbase</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the construction of lean mix concrete subbase including trial sections and subgrade beams.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1133</ID>
                  <Name>Plain and reinforced concrete base</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the construction, by mechanical or hand placement, of plain and reinforced concrete base, including trial sections, slab anchors and terminal slabs. The work also includes the construction of reinforced concrete approach slabs at bridge abutments.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1134</ID>
                  <Name>Steel fibre reinforced concrete base</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the construction of steel fibre reinforced concrete (SFRC) base and minor SFRC works for pavements including mixing, transportation, placing, finishing and curing. It does not apply to large scale highway works.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1135</ID>
                  <Name>Continuously reinforced concrete base</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the construction of continuously reinforced concrete base including mixing, transportation, placing, finishing, curing, trial sections and slab anchors.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1136</ID>
                  <Name>Cold milling of asphalt and base course</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the removal of asphalt and base course by cold milling to a specified depth, the hauling of the material to stockpiles and disposal areas and the sweeping of pavement.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>114</ID>
              <Name>Flexible pavements</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1141</ID>
                  <Name>Flexible pavement base and subbase</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the supply, spreading, compaction and trimming of flexible base and subbase courses of pavements for local roads (light to medium traffic levels). It is not applicable to highways, freeways, mine haul roads, aerodrome runways, taxiways and aprons or port facilities such as container terminals.For the purposes of this worksection, flexible base and subbase includes unbound, modified and bound materials.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1142</ID>
                  <Name>Bituminous cold mix</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the design, production and delivery of cold mix asphalt including supply of materials, sampling, testing and all other operations to provide a dense graded and open graded cold mix.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1143</ID>
                  <Name>Sprayed bituminous surfacing</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the supply of materials, design and application of bituminous seals and roadway surfacing. It also covers environmental risk assessment.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1144</ID>
                  <Name>Asphaltic concrete (Roadways)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to hot mixed, dense graded, open graded, stone mastic, fine gap graded, ultra-thin asphalt and light traffic asphalt for roadways and other pavement related applications. It includes the following:Asphalt constituent materials.Asphalt mix design.Process control in manufacture and placement of asphalt.Acceptance criteria for asphalt.Quality systems, minimum process standards, plant and sampling and testing frequencies.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1145</ID>
                  <Name>Segmental paving</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to clay and concrete segmental paving on bedding for flexible and rigid road pavements, medians, traffic islands and driveways. It includes the bedding course, supply, placement and compaction of segmental pavers and joint filling material (over various types of base and/or subbase layers). It also provides requirements for permeable pavements.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1146</ID>
                  <Name>Bituminous slurry surfacing</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the design, supply, mixing and placement of slurry seals and microsurfacing for surface correction and wearing surface applications on road pavements, carparks, cycleways and footpaths.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>115</ID>
              <Name>Road openings and restorations</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1151</ID>
                  <Name>Road openings and restoration</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to road openings and restoration for installation of underground utility services within public road reserves or reserves under Council control.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1152</ID>
                  <Name>Road openings and restoration (Utilities)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to road openings and restoration works for the installation of underground utility services within public road reserves or reserves under the control of local government authorities. It is applicable for contracts let by a public Utilities Authority and and is consistent with the objectives of the Streets Opening Coordination Council  Guide to codes and practices for streets opening and the Model Agreement for Local Councils and Utility/Service Providers prepared by the NSW Streets Opening Conference.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>116</ID>
              <Name>Rigid traffic barriers</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1163</ID>
                  <Name>Rigid road safety barrier systems</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>117</ID>
              <Name>Pavement moisture control</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1171</ID>
                  <Name>Subsurface drainage</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to provision of subsurface drainage system for roadworks including subsoil and formation drains, pavement drains and drainage blankets. It includes preparation, siting, supply of materials, general execution of subsurface drainage and recording of drain installation.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1172</ID>
                  <Name>Subsoil and foundation drains</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to drainage of ground water, seepage, springs and wet areas in subsoil and formations associated with roadworks and covers order of construction, excavation of trenches, backfilling and pavement interface drains. Read this in conjunction with 1171 Subsurface drainage (Construction) which covers preparation, siting, supply of materials, general execution of subsurface drainage and recording of drain installation.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1173</ID>
                  <Name>Pavement drains</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to drainage of ground water, seepage, springs and wet areas in subsoil and formations associated with roadworks and covers order of construction, excavation of trenches, backfilling and pavement interface drains. Read this in conjunction with 1171 Subsurface drainage (Construction) which covers preparation, siting, supply of materials, general execution of subsurface drainage and recording of drain installation.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1174</ID>
                  <Name>Drainage mats</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the installation of drainage blankets to intercept or collect subsurface water impacting the construction of roadways. Read this in conjunction with 1171 Subsurface drainage (Construction) which covers preparation, siting, supply of materials, general execution of subsurface drainage and recording of drain installation.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>119</ID>
              <Name>Traffic facilities</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1191</ID>
                  <Name>Pavement markings</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to pavement markings comprising setting out, supply and application of pavement marking paint, thermoplastic pavement marking material, two-part cold applied markings, pavement marking tape and raised pavement markers.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1192</ID>
                  <Name>Signposting</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the supply and erection of signs for roadways.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1193</ID>
                  <Name>Guide posts</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the setting out, supply of materials, excavation, placement and backfill, and erection of guide posts and delineators in areas where street lighting is not provided.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1194</ID>
                  <Name>Non-rigid road safety barrier systems</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to supply and erection of non-rigid road safety barriers and terminals in the public domain.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1195</ID>
                  <Name>Boundary fences for road reserves</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to construction of boundary fences and gates including setting out, clearing of fence line, supply of materials and components, and erection.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1196</ID>
                  <Name>Street lighting</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to construction of boundary fences and gates including setting out, clearing of fence line, supply of materials and components, and erection.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
          </Children>
        </Item>
        <Item>
          <ID>13</ID>
          <Name>CONSTRUCTION - PUBLIC UTILITIES</Name>
          <Description/>
          <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
          <Children>
            <Item>
              <ID>134</ID>
              <Name>Water supply</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1341</ID>
                  <Name>Water supply - reticulation (Construction)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the construction of water supply mains generally up to DN 375 nominal size. This worksection is aligned to the Water Services Association of Australia (WSAA) WSA 03 and is to be used with the relevant WSAA product and material specifications. It is applicable for the construction of new water supply systems or upgrading an existing water supply system.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1342</ID>
                  <Name>Water supply - pump stations (Construction)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the construction of water supply in-line booster pump stations connecting to reticulation systems generally up to DN 375 nominal size. This worksection is aligned to the Water Services Association of Australia WSA 03 and is applicable for the construction of pump stations for a new water supply or an upgrade to an existing water supply system.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>135</ID>
              <Name>Water cycle management</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1351</ID>
                  <Name>Stormwater drainage (Construction)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to earthworks, bedding and support, backfilling and compaction for drainage lines, open drains, and drainage structures. It covers common requirements for the other drainage worksections (1352 Pipe drainage, 1353 Precast box culverts, 1354 Drainage structures).</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1352</ID>
                  <Name>Pipe drainage</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the supply and installation of pipe and bolted plate structures for stormwater drainage. It includes precast reinforced concrete, fibre reinforced concrete, and plastic flexible pipes, and metal pipes and bolted structures. Read this worksection in conjunction with the 1351 Stormwater drainage (Construction) worksection which covers common requirements relating to excavation, bedding and support, compaction and backfilling for stormwater drainage.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1353</ID>
                  <Name>Precast box culverts</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the supply and installation of precast concrete box culverts. Read this worksection in conjunction with the 1351 Stormwater drainage (Construction) worksection which covers common requirements relating to excavation, bedding and support, compaction and backfilling for stormwater drainage.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1354</ID>
                  <Name>Drainage structures</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the construction of drainage structures other than pipes and precast box culverts. These may include headwalls, wingwalls, gully pits, inspection pits, junction boxes/pits, drop structures, inlet and outlet structures, energy dissipators, batter drains and other supplementary structures as documented. Read this worksection in conjunction with the 1351 Stormwater drainage (Construction) worksection which covers common requirements relating to excavation, bedding and support, compaction and backfilling for stormwater drainage, and the 1352 Pipe drainage, 1353 Precast box culverts and 1121 Open drains worksections, as applicable.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>136</ID>
              <Name>Sewerage systems</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1361</ID>
                  <Name>Sewerage systems - reticulation (Construction)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the construction of sewerage in regional council areas including the following:Gravity, pressure and vacuum sewers up to DN 600 nominal size.Rising mains up to DN 600 nominal size.Standard appurtenances such as maintenance holes, maintenance shafts and property connection sewers.This worksection is aligned to the Water Services Association of Australia WSA 02, WSA 06 and WSA 07 and is to be used with the relevant WSAA product and material specifications.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1362</ID>
                  <Name>Sewerage systems - pump stations (Construction)</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to construction of sewerage pump stations in regional Council areas, usually limited to single wells with submersible pumps.This worksection is aligned to the Water Services Association of Australia WSA 02, WSA 04, WSA 06 and WSA 07.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>139</ID>
              <Name>Others</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1391</ID>
                  <Name>Service conduits</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the supply of materials and the underground installation of electrical, telecommunications, conduits and pits. This worksection does not include trenching, excavation or backfill which is included in 1152 Road openings and restoration (Utilities).It is suitable for minor roads within the domain of urban and regional councils. For service conduits for major arterial roads or highways, refer to the requirements of the relevant State Roads Authority.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1392</ID>
                  <Name>Trenchless conduit installation</Name>
                  <Description>This worksection Template is applicable to the installation of drainage or service conduits where trenchless techniques are required. Trenchless techniques minimise interference with existing features, facilities or traffic. These techniques may be carried out either by jacking, ramming, bursting, thrust or auger boring, microtunnelling, directional drilling or other suitable techniques appropriate for the particular installation. This worksection may also be applicable for rectification of defects in existing installations.</Description>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
          </Children>
        </Item>
        <Item>
          <ID>14</ID>
          <Name>MAINTENANCE AND OPERATIONS - URBAN AND OPEN SPACES</Name>
          <Description/>
          <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
          <Children>
            <Item>
              <ID>140</ID>
              <Name>General</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1401</ID>
                  <Name>General requirements - parks and recreation areas (Maintenance)</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1402</ID>
                  <Name>Contract schedules - parks and recreation areas (Maintenance)</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1403</ID>
                  <Name>Parks and recreation areas maintenance plan (PMP)</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>141</ID>
              <Name>Horticultural</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1411</ID>
                  <Name>Street landscaping</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1412</ID>
                  <Name>Grass mowing in road reserves</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1413</ID>
                  <Name>Tree and vegetation control in road reserves</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1414</ID>
                  <Name>Weed control in road reserves</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1415</ID>
                  <Name>Weed control</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1416</ID>
                  <Name>Planting of annuals and trees</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1417</ID>
                  <Name>Care of trees and shrubs</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1418</ID>
                  <Name>Gardens</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1419</ID>
                  <Name>Care of grass and turf</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>142</ID>
              <Name>Pathways</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1420</ID>
                  <Name>Grass mowing</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1421</ID>
                  <Name>Native bushland</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1422</ID>
                  <Name>Dunal areas</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1423</ID>
                  <Name>Pest control</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1424</ID>
                  <Name>Landscape - maintenance (NATSPEC)</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>143</ID>
              <Name>Pathways</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1431</ID>
                  <Name>Footpath paving repairs</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1432</ID>
                  <Name>Gravel footpath repairs</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1433</ID>
                  <Name>Footpath and kerb ramp repairs</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>144</ID>
              <Name>Pavements</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1441</ID>
                  <Name>Bituminous surfacing repairs</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1442</ID>
                  <Name>Boat ramps</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>146</ID>
              <Name>Enclosures</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1461</ID>
                  <Name>Swimming enclosures</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1462</ID>
                  <Name>Boundary fence repair</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>147</ID>
              <Name>Equipment</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1471</ID>
                  <Name>Barbecues</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1472</ID>
                  <Name>Drinking fountains</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1473</ID>
                  <Name>Barriers</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1474</ID>
                  <Name>Lighting</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1475</ID>
                  <Name>Playground equipment</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1476</ID>
                  <Name>Park furniture</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1477</ID>
                  <Name>Sports ground facilities</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>148</ID>
              <Name>Operation - open spaces</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1481</ID>
                  <Name>Accident repairs (Recoverable)</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1482</ID>
                  <Name>Accident repairs (Non recoverable)</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1483</ID>
                  <Name>Emergency call out</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1484</ID>
                  <Name>Storm damage response</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>149</ID>
              <Name>Operation - cleaning and waste management</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1491</ID>
                  <Name>Open space litter collection</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1492</ID>
                  <Name>Open space graffiti removal</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
          </Children>
        </Item>
        <Item>
          <ID>15</ID>
          <Name>MAINTENANCE AND OPERATIONS - BUILDINGS</Name>
          <Description/>
          <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
          <Children>
            <Item>
              <ID>150</ID>
              <Name>General</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1500r</ID>
                  <Name>NATSPEC Maintenance reference</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1501</ID>
                  <Name>General requirements - buildings and facilities (Maintenance)</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1502</ID>
                  <Name>Contract schedules - buildings and facilities (Maintenance)</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1503</ID>
                  <Name>Buildings and facilities maintenance plan (BFMP)</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>153</ID>
              <Name>Structures</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1531</ID>
                  <Name>Floors</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1532</ID>
                  <Name>Walls</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1533</ID>
                  <Name>Doorways and windows</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1534</ID>
                  <Name>Ceilings</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1535</ID>
                  <Name>Roofing</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>157</ID>
              <Name>Services</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1571</ID>
                  <Name>Mechanical systems - maintenance</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1572</ID>
                  <Name>Hydraulic systems - maintenance</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1573</ID>
                  <Name>Electrical systems - maintenance</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>158</ID>
              <Name>Operation - buildings</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1581</ID>
                  <Name>External building surveillance</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1582</ID>
                  <Name>Accident repairs management (Recoverable)</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1583</ID>
                  <Name>Emergency call out</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1584</ID>
                  <Name>Storm damage response</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1585</ID>
                  <Name>External cleaning</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1586</ID>
                  <Name>Internal cleaning</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1587</ID>
                  <Name>Sanitary cleaning</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1588</ID>
                  <Name>Window cleaning</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1589</ID>
                  <Name>Cleaning - blinds and fire proofing of curtains</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
          </Children>
        </Item>
        <Item>
          <ID>16</ID>
          <Name>MAINTENANCE AND OPERATIONS - ROADWAYS</Name>
          <Description/>
          <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
          <Children>
            <Item>
              <ID>160</ID>
              <Name>General</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1601</ID>
                  <Name>General requirements - road reserve (Maintenance)</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1602</ID>
                  <Name>Contract schedules - road reserve (Maintenance)</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1603</ID>
                  <Name>Road reserve maintenance plan (RMP)</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1604</ID>
                  <Name>Annexures to road reserve maintenance plan (RMP)</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>161</ID>
              <Name>Pavements</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1611</ID>
                  <Name>Pavement sweeping</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1612</ID>
                  <Name>Auxiliary work for reseals</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1613</ID>
                  <Name>Repairs to bituminous surfacing</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1614</ID>
                  <Name>Crack sealing</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1615</ID>
                  <Name>Local shape correction</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1616</ID>
                  <Name>Grading unsealed roads</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1617</ID>
                  <Name>Resheeting unsealed roads</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1618</ID>
                  <Name>Heavy patching</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1619</ID>
                  <Name>Minor patching</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1620</ID>
                  <Name>Pothole repair</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1621</ID>
                  <Name>Concrete pavement repairs</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1622</ID>
                  <Name>Concrete slab stabilisation</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1623</ID>
                  <Name>Emergency pavement repairs</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>163</ID>
              <Name>Shoulder</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1631</ID>
                  <Name>Edge break repair</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1632</ID>
                  <Name>Grading unsealed shoulders</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1633</ID>
                  <Name>Resheeting unsealed shoulders</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1634</ID>
                  <Name>Local scour repair</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>164</ID>
              <Name>Roadside</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1641</ID>
                  <Name>Kerb and channel (gutter) repairs</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1642</ID>
                  <Name>Traffic islands</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>165</ID>
              <Name>Pavement moisture control</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1651</ID>
                  <Name>Clear road reserve subsoil drains</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1652</ID>
                  <Name>Clear road reserve open drains</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>167</ID>
              <Name>Traffic facilities</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1671</ID>
                  <Name>Road reserve boundary fence repair</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1672</ID>
                  <Name>Road reserve fences and handrails</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1673</ID>
                  <Name>Street seats and bus shelters</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1674</ID>
                  <Name>Carriageway delineators</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1675</ID>
                  <Name>Road reserve guard fence</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1676</ID>
                  <Name>Road reserve signs</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1677</ID>
                  <Name>Road reserve guide signs</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>168</ID>
              <Name>Operation - roadways</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1681</ID>
                  <Name>Accident repairs (Recoverable)</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1682</ID>
                  <Name>Road reserve emergency call out</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1683</ID>
                  <Name>Storm damage response for road safety</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1684</ID>
                  <Name>Traffic facilities - road traffic control</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>169</ID>
              <Name>Operation - cleaning and waste management</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1691</ID>
                  <Name>Road reserve litter collection</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1692</ID>
                  <Name>Removal of graffiti visible from roads</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
          </Children>
        </Item>
        <Item>
          <ID>17</ID>
          <Name>MAINTENANCE AND OPERATIONS - BRIDGES</Name>
          <Description/>
          <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
          <Children>
            <Item>
              <ID>170</ID>
              <Name>Structures</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1701</ID>
                  <Name>Wharves and decks maintenance</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
          </Children>
        </Item>
        <Item>
          <ID>18</ID>
          <Name>MAINTENANCE AND OPERATIONS - PUBLIC UTILITIES</Name>
          <Description/>
          <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
          <Children>
            <Item>
              <ID>184</ID>
              <Name>Water supply</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1841</ID>
                  <Name>Water supply - irrigation systems</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>185</ID>
              <Name>Water cycle management</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1851</ID>
                  <Name>Clear open space and drains</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1852</ID>
                  <Name>Clear open space drainage culverts</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1853</ID>
                  <Name>Clear road reserve culverts and pits</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1854</ID>
                  <Name>Minor repair of lined drains in road reserve</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1859</ID>
                  <Name>CCTV inspection of drainage conduits</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
            <Item>
              <ID>188</ID>
              <Name>Operation - cleaning and waste management</Name>
              <Description/>
              <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
              <Children>
                <Item>
                  <ID>1881</ID>
                  <Name>Beach cleaning</Name>
                  <Description/>
                  <Availability>ModelElement</Availability>
                  <Children/>
                </Item>
              </Children>
            </Item>
          </Children>
        </Item>
      </Items>
    </System>
  </Classification>
</BuildingInformation>
